[
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "Who is a fictional character in comic books?",
        "sentence": "\nLois Lane is a fictional character appearing in American comic books published by DC Comics ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "DC Comics",
        "question": "Who publishes Lois Lane's comic books?",
        "sentence": "\nLois Lane is a fictional character appearing in American comic books published by DC Comics ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joe Shuster",
        "question": "Along with Jerry Siegel, what artist created the character?",
        "sentence": "Created by writer Jerry Siegel and artist Joe Shuster , she first appeared in Action Comics # 1 ( June 1938 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Jerry Siegel",
        "question": "Who was the writer of Action Comics # 1?",
        "sentence": "Created by writer Jerry Siegel and artist Joe Shuster , she first appeared in Action Comics # 1 ( June 1938 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joe Shuster",
        "question": "Along with Jerry Siegel, what artist created the character?",
        "sentence": "Created by writer Jerry Siegel and artist Joe Shuster , she first appeared in Action Comics # 1 ( June 1938 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Action Comics",
        "question": "What was the name of the first comic she appeared in?",
        "sentence": "Created by writer Jerry Siegel and artist Joe Shuster , she first appeared in Action Comics # 1 ( June 1938 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "June 1938",
        "question": "When did she first appear in Action Comics #1?",
        "sentence": "Created by writer Jerry Siegel and artist Joe Shuster , she first appeared in Action Comics # 1 ( June 1938 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Clark Kent",
        "question": "Who is Superman's alter ego?",
        "sentence": "Lois is an award - winning journalist for the Metropolis newspaper the Daily Planet and the primary love interest of the superhero Superman and his alter ego , Clark Kent ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois",
        "question": "Who is the primary love interest of Superman?",
        "sentence": "Lois is an award - winning journalist for the Metropolis newspaper the Daily Planet and the primary love interest of the superhero Superman and his alter ego , Clark Kent ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Daily Planet",
        "question": "What newspaper does Lois work for?",
        "sentence": "Lois is an award - winning journalist for the Metropolis newspaper the Daily Planet and the primary love interest of the superhero Superman and his alter ego , Clark Kent ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Jon Kent",
        "question": "Who is the current Superboy in the DC Universe?",
        "sentence": "In DC continuity , she is also his wife and the mother of their son , Jon Kent , the current Superboy in the DC Universe ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joe Shuster",
        "question": "Who hired Joanne Carter?",
        "sentence": "Lois ' physical appearance was originally based on Joanne Carter , a model hired by Joe Shuster ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joanne Carter",
        "question": "Who was Lois based off of?",
        "sentence": "Lois ' physical appearance was originally based on Joanne Carter , a model hired by Joe Shuster ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joe Shuster",
        "question": "Who hired Joanne Carter?",
        "sentence": "Lois ' physical appearance was originally based on Joanne Carter , a model hired by Joe Shuster ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Glenda Farrell",
        "question": "Who played Torchy Blane in a series of films?",
        "sentence": "For her character , Jerry Siegel was inspired by actress Glenda Farrell 's portrayal of the fictional reporter Torchy Blane in a series of films ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Torchy Blane",
        "question": "What fictional reporter was Jerry Siegel inspired by?",
        "sentence": "For her character , Jerry Siegel was inspired by actress Glenda Farrell 's portrayal of the fictional reporter Torchy Blane in a series of films ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lola Lane",
        "question": "What actress did Siegel take her name from?",
        "sentence": "Siegel took her name from actress Lola Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lola Lane",
        "question": "What actress did Siegel take her name from?",
        "sentence": "Siegel took her name from actress Lola Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "comics",
        "question": "In what form of media has the character been depicted?",
        "sentence": "Depictions of the character have varied spanning the comics and other media adaptations ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "Who is Lois Lane intellectually equal to?",
        "sentence": "The originalversion of Lois Lane , as well as versions of her from the 1970s onwards , portrays Lois as a dauntless journalist and intellectually equal to Superman ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "Who was the original version of?",
        "sentence": "The originalversion of Lois Lane , as well as versions of her from the 1970s onwards , portrays Lois as a dauntless journalist and intellectually equal to Superman ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Gwenda Bond",
        "question": "Who wrote Lois Lane?",
        "sentence": "Beginning in 2015 , she is the protagonist in the young adult novel series , Lois Lane , by writer Gwenda Bond ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "What is the name of the young adult novel series by Gwenda Bond?",
        "sentence": "Beginning in 2015 , she is the protagonist in the young adult novel series , Lois Lane , by writer Gwenda Bond ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "2015",
        "question": "When did Lois Lane begin?",
        "sentence": "Beginning in 2015 , she is the protagonist in the young adult novel series , Lois Lane , by writer Gwenda Bond ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois",
        "question": "Who is one of the best known female comic book characters?",
        "sentence": "Lois has appeared in various media adaptations and is among the best - known female comic book characters ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Margot Kidder",
        "question": "Who played Superman in the 1970s and 1980s?",
        "sentence": "Margot Kidder played the character in four Superman films in the 1970s and 1980s , Kate Bosworth in the 2006 film Superman Returns , and Amy Adams in the DC Extended Universe ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Amy Adams",
        "question": "Who played Superman in the DC Extended Universe?",
        "sentence": "Margot Kidder played the character in four Superman films in the 1970s and 1980s , Kate Bosworth in the 2006 film Superman Returns , and Amy Adams in the DC Extended Universe ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Teri Hatcher",
        "question": "Who portrayed Lois in the 1990s television series?",
        "sentence": "Teri Hatcher portrayed Lois in the 1990s television seriesand Erica Durance in the 2000s series Smallville ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Erica Durance",
        "question": "Who portrayed Lois in the 2000s series Smallville?",
        "sentence": "Teri Hatcher portrayed Lois in the 1990s television seriesand Erica Durance in the 2000s series Smallville ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Elizabeth Tulloch",
        "question": "Who plays Superman & Lois?",
        "sentence": "Elizabeth Tulloch currently plays the character in the Arrowverse television series Superman & Lois ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman & Lois",
        "question": "What Arrowverse series does Elizabeth Tulloch play?",
        "sentence": "Elizabeth Tulloch currently plays the character in the Arrowverse television series Superman & Lois ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Dana Delany",
        "question": "Who voiced Lois in Superman : The Animated Series?",
        "sentence": "Actresses who have voiced Lois in animated adaptations include Joan Alexander in the Fleischer Superman animated film series and Dana Delany in Superman : The Animated Series , among others ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joan Alexander",
        "question": "Which actress voiced Lois in Fleischer Superman?",
        "sentence": "Actresses who have voiced Lois in animated adaptations include Joan Alexander in the Fleischer Superman animated film series and Dana Delany in Superman : The Animated Series , among others ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Glenda Farrell",
        "question": "Who played Torchy Blane in the Warner Bros. films?",
        "sentence": "One of the major influence on Lois ' characterization was actress Glenda Farrell and her portrayal of the fictional reporter Torchy Blane in a series of Warner Bros. films ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Torchy Blane",
        "question": "What fictional reporter did Glenda Farrell portray?",
        "sentence": "One of the major influence on Lois ' characterization was actress Glenda Farrell and her portrayal of the fictional reporter Torchy Blane in a series of Warner Bros. films ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "Who was the original art model for Superman?",
        "sentence": "On the conception of Lois Lane , Siegel stated in the 1988 Time magazine : My wife Joanne was Joe 's original art model for Superman 's girlfriendback in the 1930s ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "grabbing scoops",
        "question": "What was our heroine's priority?",
        "sentence": "Our heroine was , of course , a working girl whose priority was grabbing scoops ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "What was the name of my character that appealed to me?",
        "sentence": "Because the name of the actress Lola Lane ( who also played Torchy ) appealed to me , I called my character Lois Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Torchy",
        "question": "What character did Lola Lane play?",
        "sentence": "Because the name of the actress Lola Lane ( who also played Torchy ) appealed to me , I called my character Lois Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lola Lane",
        "question": "What actress did I call my character Lois Lane?",
        "sentence": "Because the name of the actress Lola Lane ( who also played Torchy ) appealed to me , I called my character Lois Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois",
        "question": "What character is remarkably similar to the real life personality of my lovely wife?",
        "sentence": "Strangely , the characterization of Lois is amazingly like the real - life personality of my lovely wife ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joe Shuster",
        "question": "Who based Lois' physical appearance on a model named Joanne Carter?",
        "sentence": "Artist Joe Shuster based Lois ' physical appearance on a model named Joanne Carter ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joanne Carter",
        "question": "Who did Joe Shuster base Lois' appearance on?",
        "sentence": "Artist Joe Shuster based Lois ' physical appearance on a model named Joanne Carter ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joe Shuster",
        "question": "Who based Lois' physical appearance on a model named Joanne Carter?",
        "sentence": "Artist Joe Shuster based Lois ' physical appearance on a model named Joanne Carter ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "Who did Shuster hire her as a model for?",
        "sentence": "Shuster corresponded with her and hired her as the model for Lois Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Shuster",
        "question": "Who hired Lois Lane as a model?",
        "sentence": "Shuster corresponded with her and hired her as the model for Lois Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "Who did Shuster hire her as a model for?",
        "sentence": "Shuster corresponded with her and hired her as the model for Lois Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "hairstyle and facial features",
        "question": "What did Shuster model Lois?",
        "sentence": "Shuster 's depiction of Lois was modeled on her hairstyle and facial features . \""
    },
    {
        "answer": "Shuster",
        "question": "Who modeled Lois' hairstyle and facial features?",
        "sentence": "Shuster 's depiction of Lois was modeled on her hairstyle and facial features . \""
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois",
        "question": "Who was Shuster's character?",
        "sentence": "Shuster 's depiction of Lois was modeled on her hairstyle and facial features . \""
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "To me, who was she?",
        "sentence": "To me she was Lois Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Joe Shuster",
        "question": "Who did Carter say was redrawing the strip for Lois Lane?",
        "sentence": "On working with Joe Shuster for Lois Lane , Carter said in the 1983 Nemo magazine interview : \" Joe was redrawing the strip , and it was going to be more realistic , rather than cartoony ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "Who did Joe Shuster work for?",
        "sentence": "On working with Joe Shuster for Lois Lane , Carter said in the 1983 Nemo magazine interview : \" Joe was redrawing the strip , and it was going to be more realistic , rather than cartoony ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "June 1938",
        "question": "When did Lois Lane first appear in Action Comics #1?",
        "sentence": "Lois Lane made her debut in Action Comics # 1 ( June 1938 ) the first published Superman story ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Action Comics",
        "question": "What was the name of Lois Lane's first comic book?",
        "sentence": "Lois Lane made her debut in Action Comics # 1 ( June 1938 ) the first published Superman story ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois Lane",
        "question": "Who made her debut in Action Comics # 1?",
        "sentence": "Lois Lane made her debut in Action Comics # 1 ( June 1938 ) the first published Superman story ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Action Comics",
        "question": "What was the name of Lois Lane's first comic book?",
        "sentence": "Lois Lane made her debut in Action Comics # 1 ( June 1938 ) the first published Superman story ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Ella and Sam Lane",
        "question": "Who are Lois Lane's parents?",
        "sentence": "Lois is the daughter of Ella and Sam Lane , in earlier comics , her parents were farmers in a town called Pittsdale ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Pittsdale",
        "question": "Where were Lois Lane's parents farmers?",
        "sentence": "Lois is the daughter of Ella and Sam Lane , in earlier comics , her parents were farmers in a town called Pittsdale ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Ramstein Air Base",
        "question": "Where was Lois born?",
        "sentence": "The modern comics depicts Lois as a former Army brat , born at Ramstein Air Base with Lois having been trained by her father , a US Army General , in areas such as hand - to - hand combat and the use of firearms ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Army brat",
        "question": "What was Lois' father's occupation?",
        "sentence": "The modern comics depicts Lois as a former Army brat , born at Ramstein Air Base with Lois having been trained by her father , a US Army General , in areas such as hand - to - hand combat and the use of firearms ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lucy Lane",
        "question": "What is the name of her younger sister?",
        "sentence": "She has one younger sibling , her sister Lucy Lane ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Daily Planet",
        "question": "What newspaper does Lois work for?",
        "sentence": "Lois is a journalist for the Daily Planet , one of the best investigative reporters and the best at the newspaper she works at ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Earth 2",
        "question": "Where are some of Lois's superhero identities located?",
        "sentence": "Lois has shown obtaining superpowers and becoming a superhero , some of her superhero identities areandof Earth 2 ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lois",
        "question": "Who has shown obtaining superpowers and becoming a superhero?",
        "sentence": "Lois has shown obtaining superpowers and becoming a superhero , some of her superhero identities areandof Earth 2 ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "comic book writers",
        "question": "Who handled Lois' character?",
        "sentence": "Aspects of Lois ' personality have varied over the years , depending on the comic book writers handling of the character and American social attitudes toward women at the time ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "American social attitudes toward women",
        "question": "Aside from the comic book writers handling of Lois, what other factors have influenced Lois' personality?",
        "sentence": "Aspects of Lois ' personality have varied over the years , depending on the comic book writers handling of the character and American social attitudes toward women at the time ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "contemporary fashion or media adaptations",
        "question": "What has influenced her physical appearance over the years?",
        "sentence": "Her physical appearance has varied over the years , depending either on contemporary fashion or media adaptations ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "violet",
        "question": "What color were Lois' eyes?",
        "sentence": "In the 1990s , when the television seriesbegan airing Lois received a haircut that made her look more like actress Teri Hatcher , and her eyes were typically violet to match her character on Superman : The Animated Series ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Teri Hatcher",
        "question": "What actress did Lois look like in the 1990s?",
        "sentence": "In the 1990s , when the television seriesbegan airing Lois received a haircut that made her look more like actress Teri Hatcher , and her eyes were typically violet to match her character on Superman : The Animated Series ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "auburn hair",
        "question": "What type of hair was she depicted with in comic books?",
        "sentence": "From the late 1980s through the 1990s she was depicted with auburn hair in the comic books ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "comic books",
        "question": "Where was she depicted with auburn hair from the late 1980's through the 1990's?",
        "sentence": "From the late 1980s through the 1990s she was depicted with auburn hair in the comic books ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Girl Reporter",
        "question": "What was the name of Lois Lane's newspaper comic strip?",
        "sentence": "In the 1940s , Lois had a newspaper comic strip , Lois Lane , Girl Reporter , a direct spin - off of the Superman comic strip running at the time ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman",
        "question": "Lois Lane, Girl Reporter was a direct spin off of what comic strip?",
        "sentence": "In the 1940s , Lois had a newspaper comic strip , Lois Lane , Girl Reporter , a direct spin - off of the Superman comic strip running at the time ."
    }
]